Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to Reel Tapes, 1961-1984
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Reel to reel tapes with Mikhashoff as performer or composer, 1961-1984, I.; Item 1-123
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 119, 1961/1984, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Hispania Performers: Mikhashoff?, piano Recording location: Unknown Annotated as "copia" Derivative files created: 3 (Box 8, Item 119)
    Contents: Scelsi: Hispania for solo piano
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_119_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_119_01-01pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_119_01-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 120, 1961/1984, 1 5.75 inch reel; Container title: Scelsi Performers: Mikhashoff? Recording location: Unknown Recorded om both sides - side 2 starts with Incantesimi Likely that Mikhashoff is the performer here; he premièred some of Scelsi's piano works in Rome, 1977 and London, 1979 Derivative files created: 1 (Box 9, Item 120)
    Contents: Scelsi: Suite No. 9 (TTAI) -- Incantesimi -- Sonata no.2
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_120_01am.wav, ubmu0001_4_120_02am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_120_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_120_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_120_02-02pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_120_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_120_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_120_02-02sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 121, 1961/1984, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Scelsi - Aitsi Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: Unknown Derivative files created: 3 (Box 9, Item 121)
    Contents: Scelsi: Aitsi (for pianoforte solo)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_121_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_121_01-01pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_121_01-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 122, 1961/1984, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Unknown solo piano works Performers: Mikhashoff? Recording location: Unknown location Recorded on both sides Note on container: Middle of Side two: Moran and Thomson waltzes, then X - Bartok: The Chase Derivative files created: 1 (Box 9, Item 122)
    Contents: Moran: Waltzes; Thomson: Waltzes; Bartók: The Chase
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_122_01am.wav, ubmu0001_4_122_02am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_122_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_122_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_122_02-02pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_122_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_122_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_122_02-02sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 123, 1982-07-10, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Christian Wolff Preludes, New Music America '82 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: Chicago, Illinois Label on container from WFMT, Chicago Derivative files created: 2 (Box 9, Item 123)
    Contents: Wolff: Preludes
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_123_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_123_01-01pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_123_01-01sc.mp3
- Reel to reel tapes of accompanying tape parts for performances, 1961-1984, II.; Item 124-142
  Contains tape parts to accompany live performances.
  Alphabetically arranged by container title.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 124, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Austin - Sonata concertante (1) First installment cue tapes: first 610 sec, 10 score pages; see letters accompanying item 125 (Box 9, Item 124)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 125, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Austin - Sonata concertante (2) Cue tape 2: all of the piece, 19 score pages; includes letters from Larry Austin to Mikhashoff (Box 9, Item 125)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 126, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Austin - Sonata concertante (3) - 1984, revised 1985 Tape part for concert performance; 4 tracks: computer, computer, blank, cue (Box 9, Item 126)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 127, undated, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Dashow - Mnemonics Recording location: Tape part for concert performance; includes a score sheet with updates and comments; a note on the back of the container gives performance instructions; probably performed in concert at UB; see note on back of container: "Steve [Bradley], this is for April 19 performance" (Box 9, Item 127)
    Contents: Dashow: Mnemonics (for violin and tape)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 128, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Daugherty Tape part for concert performance; composed in 1973 (Box 9, Item 128)
    Contents: Daugherty: Ivar's two-step
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 129, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Davidovsky Tape part for concert performance; signed by Mikhashoff; slide of one score page laid in container; composed in 1972 (Box 9, Item 129)
    Contents: Davidovsky: Synchronisms no.6
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 130, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Dodge - Any Resemblance Performers: Tape part for concert performance; signed in red by YM. (Box 9, Item 130)
    Contents: Dodge: Any resemblance is purely coincidental
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 131, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Felder - Three Nocturnes Tape part for concert performance; composed in 1973 (Box 9, Item 131)
    Contents: Felder: Three nocturnes: No.3 Colleccium nocturna
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 132, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Haiku Tape part for concert performance; composed in 1987; includes a note from Montague to Mikhashoff, 13 September 1989, concerning a possible performance in Buffalo (Box 9, Item 132)
    Contents: Montague: Haiku
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 133, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Hudson - Reflexives for tape and piano (Box 9, Item 133)
    Contents: Hudson: Reflexives
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 134, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Ivey - Skaniadaryo (1) Tape part for concert performance; composed in 1973; see also item 148 (Box 9, Item 134)
    Contents: Ivey: Skaniadaryo (for piano and tape)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 135, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Kagel - '1898' Recording location: Tape part for concert performance; annotated as: "Kinderstimmen zur Tonbandeinspielung fur Konzertfassung [Children's voices for concert version] Kopie 15 Mai 1974" (Box 9, Item 135)
    Contents: Kagel: 1898
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 136, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Keane - Lyra Tape part for concert performance. (Box 9, Item 136)
    Contents: Keane: Lyra
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 137, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Kolb - Solitaire Tape part for concert performance; the entire composition was performed 13 Feb 1972. (Box 9, Item 137)
    Contents: Kolb: Solitaire
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 138, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: McNabb Performers: Recording location: Tape part for concert performance; includes leaflet with directions for audio setup by the composer; composed 1981, revised 1983 (Box 9, Item 138)
    Contents: McNabb: Love in the asylum
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 139, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Pederson - Sonata I Hvidt Performers: Tape part for concert performance; instructions for pianist on inside of container (Box 9, Item 139)
    Contents: Pederson: Sonata i hvidt (for piano and tape)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 140, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Subotnick - Prelude No.3 Tape part for concert performance (Box 9, Item 140)
    Contents: Subotnick: Prelude no.3 for piano and electronic sounds
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 141, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Subotnick - Prelude No.4 Tape part for concert performance (Box 9, Item 141)
    Contents: Subotnick: Prelude no.4 for piano and electronic sounds
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 142, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Szekely Annotated ZKV Kolcso[nanyay] (Box 9, Item 142)
    Contents: Szekely: Concerto for piano and tape
- Reel to reel tapes without Mikhashoff as performer or composer, 1961-1984, III.; Item 143-173
  Contains recordings collected by Mikhashoff from various sources.
  Arranged chiefly in chronological order, with undated content at the end of the sequence.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 143, 1968, 1906, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1968 Strauss plays Richard Strauss Performers: Commercial reel tape of a Welte piano roll recording; transfered to tape in 1968 (Box 9, Item 143)
    Contents: Strauss: Fragments (Salome) -- Dance of the seven veils (Salome) -- An einsamer Quelle op.9 no.2 -- Love scene (Ein Heldenleben) -- Reverie op.9 no.4 -- Intermezzo op.9 no.3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 144, 1969, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1969 Kramer (1) Performers: (Box 10, Item 144)
    Contents: Kramer: Music for piano no.2
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 145, March 1971, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1971 Bruen (1) Performers: Recording location: (Box 10, Item 145)
    Contents: Bruen: Trials of psyche, opera in one act
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 146, 1972, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1972 Kramer (2) Performers: (Box 10, Item 146)
    Contents: Kramer: Music for piano no. 4
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 147, 12 March 1972, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: 1972 Larry Baker (Box 10, Item 147)
    Contents: Baker: Trimophony
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 148, September 1973, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: 1973 Ivey - Skaniadaryo (2) Performers: Complete performance; tape part for concert performance available; see item 134 (Box 10, Item 148)
    Contents: Ivey: Skaniadaryo for piano and tape
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 149, August 1975, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: 1975 Cummings Performers: Recording location: (Box 10, Item 149)
    Contents: Cummings: Bone songs
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 150, 14 August 1976, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: 1976 Baker (Box 10, Item 150)
    Contents: Baker: Musicpiece I for solo percussion -- Musicpiece II for percussion and piano
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 151, February 1977, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1977 Bruen (2) Performers: Recording location: (Box 10, Item 151)
    Contents: Bruen: Grand duo for soprano saxophone and piano -- Grand duo for flute and piano -- Five nocturnes
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 152, 1977, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1977 Messiaen - Canyons aus Etoiles Performers: Recording location: Copy of commercial recording STU 70975 (Box 10, Item 152)
    Contents: Messiaen: Canyons aux etoiles
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 153, 29 April 1977, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1977 Willey Performers: Recording location: (Box 10, Item 153)
    Contents: Willey: Second piano sonata
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 154, 17 February 1980 and 24 February 1980, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1980 Palmer - Four Decades (1) Performers: Recording location: Program notes by the composer (Box 10, Item 154)
    Contents: Palmer: First sonata- Second sonata -- Toccata ostinato -- Epigrams VIII-XI -- Transitions -- Third sonata
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 155, 17 February 1980-24 February 1980, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1980 Palmer - Four Decades (2) Performers: Recording location: (Box 10, Item 155)
    Contents: see part 1, item 154
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 156, May 1981, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: 1981 Phillips / Willey Performers: Includes a letter from James Willey to Mikhashoff, dated 18 May 1981: Willey evaluates the recordings on this tape, reviews his recent visit to Buffalo, and discusses plans for a concert at Geneseo with participation of Mikhashoff (Box 10, Item 156)
    Contents: Philipps: Piano sonata no.3 -- Willey: Some old refrains -- The musical miscellany
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 157, 1982, 1 6 inch disc; Container title: 1982 Schafer Performers: Commercial recording; first work prepared for an exhibition of sound sculpture organized by the National Museums Corporation of Canada; the second work is a novel read by Schafer (Box 10, Item 157)
    Contents: Schafer: Here the sounds go round -- Introduction to smoke
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 158, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Barcelona (1) - Berenguer Recording location: (Box 10, Item 158)
    Contents: Berenguer: El vent del capvespre
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 159, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Barcelona (2) - Capdevila Recording location: (Box 10, Item 159)
    Contents: Capdevila: Gramatges
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 160, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Barcelona (3) - Polonio Recording location: (Box 11, Item 160)
    Contents: Polonio: De fantasia variaciones bajo fianza rabelais en un trono
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 161, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Barcelona (5) - Lewin-Richter Recording location: (Box 11, Item 161)
    Contents: Lewis-Richter: Secuenzia IV
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 162, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Bieler (Box 11, Item 162)
    Contents: Bieler: Esothen fur Flugel innen
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 163, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Constantinides (Box 11, Item 163)
    Contents: Constantinides: Sonata for solo piano
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 164, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Jewish Chronicle (commercial) Commercial recording; however, the work was also performed at Buffalo on 13 March 1977; this marks the first Buffalo appearance of Uitti; Mikhashoff was the director of the Baird Contemporary Ensemble (Box 11, Item 164)
    Contents: Blacher, Boris; Wagner-Regeny; Hartmann; Henze; Dessau
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 165, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Kubik - Piano Concerto A Czech concert took place on 8 December 1979 at UB. It included works by Kubik and Invence; see Mikhashoff document archive for program notes of this concert (Box 11, Item 165)
    Contents: Kubik: Piano concerto
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 166, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Kubik / Rezac / Jinasek (Box 11, Item 166)
    Contents: Kubik: Narek bojovne kovy zeny -- Rezak: ISR -- Jinasek: Portret Zeny
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 167, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Miroglio - Soleils (Box 11, Item 167)
    Contents: Miroglio: Soleils
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 168, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Patachich - Ludispaziali Performers: Item contains both complete music and a tape part for concert performance (Box 11, Item 168)
    Contents: Patachich: Ludispaziali for piano and tape
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 169, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Scelsi Performers: Recording location: Annotated as "Copyright G. Scelsi, no duplication"; composed in 1953 (Box 11, Item 169)
    Contents: Scelsi: Cinque incantesimi -- Suite no. 9 -- Suite no. 11 -- Suite no. 12 -- Inoutetto no. 2 -- YNOYBIS (per violino solo)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 170, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Stalvey (1) (Box 11, Item 170)
    Contents: Stalvey: Points-Lines-Circles -- Fitan
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 171, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Stalvey (2) (Box 11, Item 171)
    Contents: Stalvey: Celebration Sequent II -- Celebration Principium -- Celebration Sequent IV
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 172, undated, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Stalvey (3) (Box 11, Item 172)
    Contents: Stalvey: Celebration Sequent I -- Changes
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 173, undated, 1 5 inch reel; Container title: Willey Performers: Annotation on container: "right channel underrecorded, should be adjusted accordingly"; composed in 1975 (Box 11, Item 173)
    Contents: Willey: String quartet -- Death of Mozart
- Long playing and compact disc recordings, 1960-1996, IV.; Item 174-184
  Commercially released sound recordings containing performances by Mikhashoff.
  Arranged chiefly in chronological order.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 174, 23 May 1960, 1 33 1/3 rpm sound recording; Container title: 1960 - Barber non-commercial recording (Box 12, Item 174)
    Contents: Barber: Sonate for piano, op. 26, Fennimore: Waltzes op. 1
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 175, September 1980, May 1981, 1 33 1/3 rpm sound recording; Container title: Yvar Mikhashoff plays Johnson, Palmer, and Beeson Recorded on Composers Recordings CRI SD 464; annotated: "For the Library from Yvar with warm regards -- May 3, 1982" (Box 12, Item 175)
    Contents: Johnson, Hunter: Piano sonata; Palmer: Second piano sonata; Beeson: Fifth piano sonata
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 176, 1982, 1 33 1/3 rpm sound recording; Container title: Virgil Thomson: Sixty Years of Piano Music Recorded on Spectrum SR-153; annotated: Best regards to the UB Music Library – April 1982 (Box 12, Item 176)
    Contents: Thomson: Prelude -- Ten easy pieces and a coda -- Piano sonata no. 1 -- Suite from The plough that broke the plains -- Sixteen portraits
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 177, 12-13 June 1980, 1 33 1/3 rpm sound recording; Container title: The Waltz Project Recorded on Nonesuch D-79011; annotated: For the Music Archives and the great staff – Yvar (Box 12, Item 177)
    Contents: Moran: Waltz "In memoriam -- Maurice Ravel" -- Glass: Modern love waltz -- Babbitt: Minute waltz -- Harrison: Waltz for Evelyn Hinrichsen -- Sessions: Waltz -- Fennimore: Titles waltz: After Max Steiner -- Krauze: Music box waltz -- Tower: Red garnet waltz -- Ashforth: Sentimental waltz -- Constanten: Dejavalse -- Helps: Valse mirage -- Tcherepnin: Valse perpetuelle -- Stout: Waltz -- Gena: Waltz -- Cage: Waltzes for the five boroughs -- Thomson: For a happy occasion
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 178, 1980, 1 33 1/3 rpm sound recording; Container title: Charles Ives: Concord sonata Recorded on Spectrum SR-120; annotated: For all my friends of the Music Library – Yvar Mikhashoff – April 22, 1981 (Box 12, Item 178)
    Contents: Ives: Piano sonata no. 2, "Concord, Mass., 1840-1860"
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 179, 1986, 1 compact disc; Container title: Karlheinz Stockhausen – Mantra Recorded on New Albion NA025CD (Box 12, Item 179)
    Contents: Stockhausen: Mantra
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 180, 1946-1996, 4 compact discs; Container title: 50 Jahre Neue Musik in Darmstadt Recorded on Col Legno WWE 4 CD 31893; previously unpublished recordings (Box 12, Item 180)
    Contents: Unpublished music from the archives of the International Musikzentrum Darmstadt (IMD); covering 50 years of the New Music festival at Darmstadt
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 181, 22-25 May 1992, 1 compact disc; Container title: Incitation to desire: Tangos for Yvar Mikhashoff Recorded on New Albion NA073CD (Box 12, Item 181)
    Contents: Sahl: Exiles' cafe Carleton -- Cage: Perpetual canon (I) -- Rudhyar: Tango d'Antan -- Duckworth -- Tango -- Schimmel -- Fromage dangereux -- Foss: Curriculum vitae tango -- Pender: Ms. Jackson dances for the world -- Bennett: Tango after Syrinx -- Biscardi: Incitation to desire -- Loudova: Tango music -- Bright: Tango dreaming -- Sary: Tango -- Nancarrow: Tango? -- Hill: Tango no tango -- Raschke: Tango auf drei Beinen -- Copland: Tempo di tango -- Jaggard: Tango -- Cage: Perpetual tango (II) -- Berkman: Thorn-torn lips
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 182, 22 November 1988, 1 compact disc; Container title: Schtetl variations Recorded on Mode 49 (Box 12, Item 182)
    Contents: Curran: For Cornelius -- Last acts of Julian Beck
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 183, 18-22 February and 14 April 1992, 1 compact disc; Container title: Conlon Nancarrow: Studies Recorded on RCA Victor 09026-61180-2 (Box 12, Item 183)
    Contents: Nancarrow: Piece no. 2 for small orchestra -- Sarabande and scherzo -- Studies for player piano (arr. for instrumental ensemble by Yvar Mikhashoff): Nos. 1, 2, 3c, 5, 6, 7, 9, 12, 14, 18, 19 -- Tango (orig. for pfte.; arr. by Mikhashoff) -- Toccata (orig. for violin-pfte.; arr. by Mikhashoff) -- Trio
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Item 184, 1981, 1 compact disc; Container title: Cal Arts: Essentia Recorded on California Institue of the Arts promotional recording (non-commercial) (Box 12, Item 184)
    Contents: Compositions by students and faculty of Cal Arts
- Reel to reel tapes added from other University at Buffalo sources with Mikhashoff as performer or composer, circa 1970-1981, V.; Item 185-216
  Contains reel to reel tapes containing performances by Mikhashoff recorded at University at Buffalo events.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 185, 1961/1984, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Charles Ives: Sonata no. 2 (Concord sonata) Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: Unknown Label on container: "Edited by Mikhashoff; corrected copies (Score accompanies tape)" - this could be an entire performance or a presentation about the piece. 1 work in 2 files Derivative files created: 4 (Box 12, Item 185)
    Contents: Ives: Sonata no. 2 (Concord sonata)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_185_01am.wav, ubmu0001_4_185_02am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_185_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_185_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_185_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_185_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 186, 1961/1981, 1 7 inch reel; Container title: Prerecorded off-stage materials used for "An Ives stereopticon" Performers: Unknown Recording location: Unknown Created to accompany concert presentation performed by Mikhashoff Derivative files created: 9 (Box 12, Item 186)
    Contents: Band I: Violins - obbligato for The Housatonic at Stockbridge; Band II: Missionary chant for mixed chorus (coda of "Emerson"); Band III: Massa's in the cold, cold ground; Band IV: Chime (The Concord bell) G#
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_186_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_186_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_186_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_186_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_186_01-04pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_186_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_186_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_186_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_186_01-04sc.mp3